# FULL NAME José Rui Leal Mendes Belo LOCATION Northwich, Cheshire CONTACT INFORMATION +44 7546437241 | jr.belo@hotmail.com | github.com/CZ-RBelo

# Front End Web Developer

#### **SUMMARY**

As a tech-savvy front-end web developer, I have always had a strong gravitational pull towards technology.

With extensive experience in MS SQL and Oracle (T-SQL) database code development, now a Front Web Development Certificate at Trilogy Education Services from London, I am gaining much-needed experience in web development fundamentals while improving my skills in ES6 and Node.js, React State and Deployment, HTML5, CCS, Bootstrap and JavaScript, jQuery, and APIs (Server / Web / Third-Party).

I am always striving to improve my skills and knowledge base. I consider communication and collaboration to be fundamental parts of teamwork.

I intend to create and maintain websites, in addition to developing applications for iOS and Android.

I seek to bring my attention to detail and technical skills to a business to grow and become a valuable asset.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Node.js
- React
- APIs (Server / Web / Third-Party)
- JavaScript
- HTML and CSS
- ETL Extract, Transform and Load
- MS SQL SSIS MS SQL SSRS
- Web Designer
- UX

- Microsoft SQL Server / Oracle Developer
- Shopify / Wix / WordPress
- Access / Excel / Word
- IT Project management
- VBA

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### 2020 - Current Conceptzoa OÜ, Estonia (remote)

#### Web designer

# **Main Responsibilities**

- . Using web development tools such as WordPress, Wix or Shopify
- . Implementing and maintaining high quality SEO policies and incorporating them with web content
- . Collecting and analysing data on website usage to improve performance
- . Responding to reports of technical problems and working with the team to fix them quickly

#### 2016 – 2020 Xenon Software Hub, Ltd (remote)

#### Web designer

#### **Main Responsibilities**

- . Using web development tools such as Webador, Wix or Shopify
- . Using Systeme.io Funnels Builder, Workflows, Email marketing
- . Working with other teams to meet company-wide targets
- . Using web content management systems

### 2014 - 2015 1K4S – One Key for Solutions, Luanda, Angola

#### Team Manager / Analyst

#### **Main Responsibilities**

- . Implement SQL Server installations with policies of backups, restores, and recovery models.
- . T-SQL of SQL Server development.

- . ETL data tasks through SSIS from SQL Server; Excel; Access to SQL Server.
- . Maps and reports through SQL Reporting Services/ Crystal Reports / Excel

# 2011 - 2014 Espírito Santo Saúde - Hospital de Santiago, Setúbal, Portugal

#### Analyst / Programmer Oracle and MS SQL Server

#### **Main Responsibilities**

- . Identifying gaps and opportunities, recommending changes and improvements and formulating the action plan to help organization harness and realize significantly more value from IT.
- . Designing and implementing the overall technology to support business processes, people, and business strategy.
- . Reporting management and decision support.
- . Developing search data forms through VBA for Word and Excel files to search in Databases.

## 2009-2010 Free Lancer / Several Projects

#### **MS SQL Server Consultant**

#### **Main Responsibilities**

- . Operational support to scoping of new projects or integrating new versions, new tools of management or administration.
- . Assessing current and determining future technology and architecture requirements in support of organizational strategy.
- . Analyse of functional and/or technical needs of clients and their projects, identifying, ranking priorities and setting goals, conducting checks.
- . Setting budgets and resources by planning and meeting deadlines.

#### 2001-2008 Viagens Abreu, Lisboa, Portugal

#### **Database Administrator / Programmer MS SQL Server**

#### **Main Responsibilities**

- . Project management as Database Administrator and Coordinator of the development team.
- . Designing, development and implementation of the Integrated Business Management System and the public website.
- . Planning of major system upgrades or new projects.
- . Extract and Transform data through DTS/ DTSX from dBASE III.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

2023 (ongoing)	Front End Web Developer / Trilogy Education Services, London
	ES6 and Node.js React State and Deployment APIs (Server / Web / Third-Party) JavaScript HTML and CSS UX
2015	Querying MS SQL Server 2012 / O'Reilly Media
	Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Certification Training Exam - 70-461
2014	Crystal Reports – Advanced / Primavera Academy, Lisbon
2013	Primavera Project Management / Primavera Academy, Lisbon
2012 (Unfinished)	Business Administration Degree / Universidade Aberta, Lisbon